William Goff Caples Speeches 5250
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
William Goff Caples Speeches
1950-1968
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Caples, William Goff
5250
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Speeches (documents), transcripts.
Consists chiefly of copies of speeches made by Caples (few originals, few reprints) before workingmen's associations, management conferences, civic and social groups, and educational institutes in his capacity as an Inland Steel Company executive.
2293768
Biographical / Historical
William Goff Caples was born in Pittsburgh October 4, 1909. He graduated from Kenyon College in 1930 and from Northwestern University Law School in 1933. He was admitted to the Illinois bar in 1933 and practiced in Chicago from 1933 to 1938.
From 1938 to 1942 he was general attorney to the Continental Casualty Company. He served overseas with the Army Engineer Corps during the war and was discharged to the Reserves as Lt.Col. in 1946.
He was manager of industrial relations at Inland Steel Company from 1946-1950, president and director of its subsidiary, Inland Steel Container Company from 1950-53, returning to Inland Steel Company as vice president in 1953.
He has been president of the Chicago Board of Education and of the United Charities of Chicago. Mr. Caples is very active in many industrial relations and humanitarian groups. His present activities include memberships in: the Advisory Council of the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, the American Iron and Steel Institute, American Management Association, Industrial Relations Research Association, and Industrial Relations Association of Chicago.
His publications are: "The Traditional Role of Management," Current History, July 1965; "The Economy, Our Government and Collective Bargaining," Reporting, March 1965; "A Management Viewpoint," Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, January 1961. His interests have been: Collective Bargaining, Personnel Administration and Industrial Sociology.
In September 1968 he became president of Kenyon College in Gambier, Ohio.
Sources: Who's Who in America, 1968-69;' Membership Directory, 1966 of the Industrial Relations Research Association and the Wall Street Journal.
Scope and Contents
The speeches deal with employee benefits plans, employment security, collective bargaining, industrial management, economic education, women workers, training, staffing and minority workers, frustration, pensions, labor and materials security, social problems, race relations, social change, middle management, social security, automation, collectivism, union mergers, recruitment, management development, management policy, education and opportunity, industrial relations and public opinion, female education, labor education, the iron and steel industry, labor-management cooperation, union policy, labor legislation, technological changes, executive ability, prejudice, equal employment opportunity, job choice, management responsibility, education policy, unemployment, industrial economics, personnel management, discrimination in employment, older workers, retirement, on-the-job training, and human, industrial, and public relations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
R. Miles, April 28, 2003
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 22, 2017
Age and employment -- United States; Automation -- Social aspects -- United States; Collective bargaining -- United States; Discrimination in employment -- United States; Educational equalization -- United States; Employee fringe benefits -- United States; Employees -- Training of -- United States; Executives -- Training of -- United States; Industrial management -- United States; Job security -- United States; Labor laws and legislation -- United States; Middle managers -- United States; Minorities -- Employment -- United States; Personnel management -- United States; Psychology, Industrial -- United States; Public relations -- United States; Retirement -- United States; Social security -- United States; Technological innovations -- United States; Unemployment -- United States; Vocational guidance -- United States; Women -- Education -- United States; Women -- Employment -- United States; Executives.; Personnel directors; Industrial relations -- United States -- Public opinion; Labor-management cooperation -- United States; Steel industry and trade -- United States; Labor unions -- Mergers -- United States; Workers' education -- United States; United States -- Race relations; United States -- Social conditions; Caples, William Goff, 1909-; Inland Steel Company
2293768
- Speches, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Speches, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Speches, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Speches, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Speches, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Speches, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Speches, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Speches, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Speches, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Speches, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Speches, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Speches, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Speches, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Speches, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Speches, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)